Hey, guys.
Hey. Honey, I got
us that room
at the Woodford
Inn this weekend.
That place in Vermont?
You can take a hint!
Wait, you can't go
away this weekend.
It's Emma's birthday.
Yeah.
We're having a party.
Well, can't you just
have the party when we get back?
No.
Then it won't be
her real birthday.
Gee, if only
she were one and had no idea
what the hell a birthday was.
Come on, you guys,
this is really important to us.
Well, I'm sorry,
but Chandler and I could
really use a weekend away,
you know, to reconnect
emotionally.
There's this thing
I really want us to do.
I read about it in Maxim.
Well, can't you just go
to Vermont the next day?
Yeah, we want everyone
to be there,
as much as I hate to delay
your doing weird sex stuff
to my little sister.
RACHEL:
And I mean, you know,
you guys, this
is a big deal.
I mean, how can
we have her first
birthday party
without her aunt
and her uncle?
All right, we'll stay.
We can just drive up
after the party.
Fine. But if
we end up
not doing this Maxim thing
because of this party...
Believe me, that is not
why we won't be doing that.
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's D.O.A. ♪
♪ It's like you're always
stuck in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been
your day, your week ♪
♪ Your month,
or even your year ♪
♪ But I'll be there for you ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me, too. ♪
You know, Pheebs,
when I was little,
on my birthday,
my daddy would hide a present
in every room of the house.
And then he would draw
a treasure map
to help me find them all.
Oh. I love family
traditions like that.
When, um... when Ursula
and I were kids,
on our birthday,
our stepdad would
sell his blood
to buy us food.
Hey, you guys.
Hi.
Hey.
Hi. I brought the camera
for Emma's video.
Oh, good, good.
We had this idea
to make a birthday video
for Emma,
and we'll give it to her
when she's 18.
Oh, cool. Wow!
It's like a time capsule.
ROSS:
Yeah.
Oh, just think, she's going
to being watching that video
on a TV that hasn't even
been invented yet.
With friends who, right now,
are just, like, babies.
And they'll live
in a floating city
that the humans built
to escape the Ant People.
That's the hope.
So, is, uh,
Emma awake yet?
Oh, no, it's still nap time,
but she'll be up soon.
Oh. Where's Joey?
I said it's still nap time.
ROSS:
Hey.
There's Uncle Joey.
Hey, say
something to Emma
on her eighteenth
birthday.
18, huh?
Joey, no!
What?
What? It's for her hot friends.
When they see this,
you'll be 52.
And starting to think
about settling down.
Hey, Joey,
will you please
set this up
for people to put
Emma's presents on?
Love to, yeah.
We were supposed
to bring presents?
Yeah. I wrote Emma a song.
Oh, yeah.
How was I supposed to know?
Well, Joey, it's
a birthday party.
Yeah, but for a one-year-old.
What's the point?
The other day she laughed
for, like, an hour at a cup.
Just a cup with a picture
of Elmo on it
dressed as a farmer.
And he's standing next
to this cow,
and the cow says, "El-mooo!"
Man...
that's a funny cup.
Hey.
Hey. Where's the
birthday girl?
Oh, she's
still napping.
Oh, sure, she was
probably up all night
excited about the
party she knows
is happening.
Look, I know that you guys
really want to get to Vermont,
and this isn't a really
big deal to you.
But it really is to us, okay?
Emma will never have
a first birthday again.
All right, you're right.
We're sorry.
Now, let's wake up Emma
and get the fun times started!
No, really, she didn't
sleep well last night,
so we can't wake her up.
Are you friggin'
kidding me, Green?
( knock at door )
Hi.
Hey.
Glad you came.
I can't
believe
Emma's
already one.
Oh. I remember your
first birthday.
Ross was jealous
of all the attention
we were giving you.
He pulled on his
testicles so hard,
we had to take him
to the emergency room.
There's something
you didn't know about your dad.
Hey, Mr. and Mrs. Geller!
Let me help you with that.
Thank you.
Oh, man, this is great, huh?
The three of us together again.
You know what would be fun?
If we gave this present
to Emma from all of us.
Which one are you?
I can't believe
Emma's still asleep.
I know.
What are we going to do?
I've got a plan,
I've got a plan.
I'm going to ram this
platter really hard
into your ribs, okay?
You're going
to scream out,
and that will
wake her up!
I'm not going
to Vermont with this Monica.
Hey, Pheebs,
you know what?
I was thinking,
since you wrote a song,
maybe I could do something
for Emma using my talents.
So, you're going to...
hit on her? What...
No, no, no.
My talents as an actor.
Oh.
You know, I could,
like, maybe...
I could do a dramatic reading
of one of her books.
Or you could stick
a fork in an apple.
Hey, I think Emma might like it.
Oh, Emma might like what?
Um... my present.
What did you get her?
Actually,
we prepared performances.
Well, separate
performances.
But equally real.
Well, that sounds like fun.
Well, you now what, actually?
People are getting
a little antsy
waiting for Emma to wake up
from her nap,
so would you mind
performing them once now?
Sure. Yeah.
Yeah?
Okay.
Okay, okay? All right.
Everybody, let's get
this party started, huh?
Joey and Phoebe are going
to perform a little something
for us.
Oh, great.
Aren't you going
to be embarrassed
going up there having
nothing prepared?
Hey, I do it every week
with three cameras pointing
at me
and a whole crew waiting.
RACHEL:
So, Joey,
what are you going
to do for us?
Uh, I will be doing
a dramatic reading
of one of Emma's books.
Oh. Okay.
Which one?
Uh, well, it's, uh,
one of her favorites.
Riding the Storm Out:
Coping With Postpartum
Depression.
Yeesh!
( chuckling )
Love You Forever.
Love You Forever
by Robert Munsch.
Published by Firefly Books.
Printed... in Mexico.
( Joey clears his throat )
"A mother held her new
baby, and very slowly
"rocked him back and forth,
"back and forth, back and forth.
"And while she held him,
she sang,
"I'll love you forever.
"I'll like you for always.
"As long as I'm living,
my baby you'll be.
"And while he
rocked her, he sang
"I'll love you forever.
"I'll like you for always.
As long as I'm living,
my baby you'll be."
Wow.
( crying ):
That was amazing.
Thank you so much for that gift.
( crying ):
I was not ready
for this today.
Amazing.
RACHEL:
Oh, Phoebe,
I'm sorry.
Phoebe's prepared something
as well.
PHOEBE:
That's right.
I've prepared a song for Emma,
from my heart to hers,
for there is no greater gift...
than the gift of music.
♪ Emma ♪
♪ Your name poses a dilemma ♪
♪ 'Cause not much else rhymes
with Emma ♪
♪ Maybe the actor
Richard Crenna ♪
♪ He played the commanding
officer in Rambo ♪
♪ Happy birthday, Emma. ♪
( chuckling )
Is that it?
No, of course not.
RACHEL:
Okay.
No, I've also, you know,
prepared a reading.
Um... Sex and the Single Mother.
"Finding your G spot."
No!
No, no, no!
Now, wait.
Whoa, whoa, hey.
Hello, Emma.
Happy eighteenth
birthday.
Right now that seems
so far away, 17 years.
Yes, you'll be all grown up
by then and we'll be...
Well, your grandfather
and I might not be here.
That's true.
This message could be coming to
you from beyond the grave, Emma.
After all, my parents
died very young.
And my cholesterol's
off the charts.
Remember, Emma, heart
disease kills women, too.
Okay, cut!
Great. Great.
That was... that was just...
yeah.
Ross, um, don't forget
to get a shot of Emma's cake.
It's in a box
in the fridge.
Okay, sure.
Oh, you're going
to love this cake.
I got it from a bakery
in New Jersey-- Carino's.
Oh, my God, that place has
the creamiest frosting!
I used to hitchhike
there when I was a kid!
Well, anyway, they make
these great novelty cakes
in all different shapes,
and if you give them a photo,
they'll copy it in icing.
Aw, did you do a
picture of Emma?
Yes, on a cake
shaped like a bunny!
Uh, Rach, does this bakery,
by any chance,
also bake... erotic cakes?
Say, for bachelorette parties?
Ross, what are you talking...?
Oh, my God!
They put my baby's
face on a penis!
( gasps )
Now it's a party!
Wait, you guys, this
isn't funny, all right?
If I wanted the cake
to be a disaster,
I would have
baked it myself.
Uh... is it okay that I still
think it looks delicious?
Jack, look at this.
I know what you're thinking,
Judy.
The resemblance is uncanny.
I am this close to tugging
on my testicles again.
No, no, this is not
what I ordered, okay?
I went all the way
to New Jersey
so that I could have
the perfect cake
for my daughter's birthday,
and I need a bunny cake
right now!
Ask them if it
would be faster
if we cut the baby's
face off the penis
so we could put
it on the bunny.
That is a weird sentence.
Oh, believe you me, I am going
to bring this cake back.
I don't even want it
in my home.
Joey, don't touch it!
I'm so confused!
Yes, yes, I still want
my daughter's picture,
but on a bunny cake.
Yellow cake, chocolate frosting,
with nuts.
To be fair, this
one does have nuts.
Hey, Mon, it was really nice
of you to loan Rachel
your car so she could
go get the cake.
It was so nice of her
to pull my hair
till I dropped the key.
Well, you know what,
while we're waiting,
you guys could tape your message
to Emma
for her 18th birthday, huh?
Okay...
Hi, Emma.
It's the year 2020.
Are you still
enjoying your nap?
We're Aunt Monica and Uncle
Chandler by the way.
You may not recognize us
because we haven't spoken to
your parents in 17 years.
We used to be married.
But we missed
a weekend away together
and things kind
of unraveled.
Because of you.
Happy birthday.
MONICA:
Ross, Rachel promised us
it would
be over by now.
We seriously have to go if we
want to get to Vermont.
I called and the last train
leaves in a half hour.
You know, I have
a massage client soon.
You guys,
just please,
a little bit longer.
I promise Rachel will be back
with the cake any minute.
Monica, remember the frosting?
All right,
five more minutes.
( phone ringing )
Hello.
Oh, no. What happened?
Okay, okay, where are you?
Okay, I'll be right there.
Was that Emma? Is she up?
Rachel got pulled over
for speeding.
She forgot her license, so now
I have to bring it to her.
Well, if you're leaving,
I'm definitely going to go.
Wait, if anybody
gets to go, it's us.
We've been complaining
the longest.
Wait, you guys,
you can't leave, okay.
Rachel already
feels bad that the cake's
messed up.
How do you think
she's going to feel
when she comes back here
and all you guys are gone?
I don't know.
You'll tell us on Monday.
Joey, you're in charge,
okay?
Make sure nobody leaves.
Got it.
Hey, hey, hey,
where do you think you're going?
To the bathroom?
All right. Well, the rest
of you get comfortable, okay?
Because we're going to
be here for... Wait a minute...
There's a window in there.
Oh, no. He's not
getting away that easy.
CHANDLER:
What are you doing?!
Get the hell out of here!
Well, that one did not
have Emma's face on it.
No, it did not.
No.
Well, we'd better
get going.
It's late.
Jack's not allowed
to drive at night anymore.
He has trouble staying
in his lane.
Last winter I went up
on a church lawn
and drove right through
a manger scene.
The papers thought it was
a hate crime.
Anyway, it was lovely
seeing you.
Okay.
Bye.
Nighty-night.
Joey, how could you just
let them leave?
Hey, hey, hey, I'm not
going to mess with Jack.
He's a great man.
He fought for our country.
No, he didn't.
He pretended to be a
Quaker to get out of Korea.
( gasps )
Well, that's it.
He's the last one to go.
I'm locking you guys in!
You do know I can just turn them
the other way around, right?
Oh, I forgot you used
to live here.
( phone ringing )
Hello.
Joey, it's Estelle.
Hey.
So how'd your
audition go today?
What audition?
The one I told you
about last week.
What?! You never said anything
about an audition!
Let me start over.
I just got a call
about an audition.
I think you can still make it.
It's down at the Astor Theater.
And you need to have
a monologue prepared.
A monologue? I don't have a...
I got it.
Uh, so... I'm going
to take off.
PHOEBE:
What?!
No way. You don't
get to leave!
I've got a massage client
waiting outside my door
any minute.
And we paid for a room
that we're supposed
to be in right now!
Okay, now.
Only one of us has
to stay with Emma.
Okay, and as the person
who realized that, I get to go.
No, no, no.
Let's figure out a
fair way to decide
who's staying.
Oh, I got it.
Okay, everyone pick a
number from one to ten.
All right, whoever gets the
highest number,
gets to go first.
Okay, ten.
Okay, Monica's picks ten.
I call nine.
Anyone else?
Let's just... let's just
draw straws.
Or we flip a coin,
and then multiply
the answer...
I'm begging you, stop.
Okay.
Okay, how about this?
We got wind-up toys for
Emma for her birthday.
We can make them race
and whoever comes
in last, stays.
Yeah! Let's do that!
That sounds more fun
than the thing we were
going to do in Vermont.
Okay, everybody pick a toy.
Okay.
I want the dolphin!
That's a bear.
I'm too excited!
Okay, Phoebe,
you get the bear,
Joey, you get the robot,
and Chandler and I
get the dog.
And the race
is going to go from here
to here.
Now the one who
comes in last
stays.
Okay, ladies and gentlemen,
wind your toys.
On your mark...
get set... go!
Go! Go!
Come on, robot!
( mechanical barking )
What are you barking at?!
Well, how is that
going to help?!
I bought you!
How did I forget that
that's all you do?!
Way to go, robot!
Good job, Alan!
Hey, good race, you guys.
Yeah. See you later.
Oh, no, no, no. Wait.
We didn't lose.
The rules clearly stated
that the last one
to cross the finish line
was the loser.
Well, our dog never
crossed the finish line,
so technically...
They left.
No, there isn't time
to go to the bakery.
We're just going to come home.
Everybody left?
All right, well,
just tell Emma
that we'll be there
as soon as we can.
Bye.
Rachel!
Oh, God! Sorry.
I can't believe they
gave you a ticket.
You're such a good driver.
Emma's awake.
Yeah?
I can't believe this.
It's her first birthday,
she's awake,
we're not even there.
Everybody left.
We've still have this stupid,
obscene cake.
Well, maybe I can fix that.
You know, try to turn it
into something else.
Oh, don't even bother.
We've already ruined her
first birthday.
Do you know how
important these early
experiences are, Ross?
Very, according to the back
cover of that book
that you gave me.
Rach, she's not going
to remember this.
I just had such an idea
of what this day would be like,
you know.
Emma laughing and everybody
gathered around her cake,
singing "Happy Birthday,"
And then we would
all go into...
Get off the road,
you stupid student driver!
( horn honking )
They have to learn!
Hey.
What?
It isn't that bad.
Oh my God.
You made it into a bunny.
How did you do that?
Well, I just made
these two
things cheeks.
And then I...
I split this to make ears.
Well, I'm very impressed.
Some can sing, some can dance,
I, apparently, can turn phallic
cakes into woodland creatures.
Now, another way to organize
your stuffed animals is by size.
I'm sorry, is this a game
for Emma or for Monica?
Game?
Emma,
do you even know it's
your birthday today?
You're one. One year old.
That's little.
( gurgling )
( gasps )
That's my girl.
That's how old you are.
Did I teach her that?
Did I just impart wisdom?
I want one.
Me, too.
There's no one around.
Why don't we just
take this one?
And head to Canada.
I was kidding.
I wasn't. Let's get going.
Hey, are Ross and Rachel back?
No, not yet.
Oh good, I didn't
miss the party.
What about
your massage client?
I just felt so bad missing this,
so I just slipped him
a little something, you know.
As long as I'm back in five
or six hours,
it'll be all right.
Okay, if Ross and Rachel ask,
I've been here the whole time.
The whole time.
Joey, we just saw you come in.
You ran past us on the stairs.
RACHEL:
I don't care
that you left.
I'm just glad
that you're here.
Thanks, you guys.
Hey, guys, come on.
You got to see what
Emma just did.
What?
Emma, how old are you?
How old are you today?
( all gasp )
Oh, Emma, that's right.
You're that many.
Oh, my God, our
daughter's a genius.
Rach, this means...
No, no science camp!
Damn it.
I'll put a candle
on the cake.
Oh, and, Emma, look
at your stuffed animals
lined up so neatly.
Thanks.
Okay, here we go.
Emma's first
birthday cake.
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
Oh, yeah, nothing.
These are happy tears.
This is just what I wanted.
Hey, you made it
into a bunny.
What is wrong with me?
It looked more delicious
when it was a penis.
Okay.
Okay, you ready?
Yeah.
And... record.
Okay.
Hi, Emma.
Well, your first
birthday is over.
( loud shouting )
CHANDLER:
No! No! No!
Go! Go! Go, Alan!
Run you hairy bastard!
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org